

MASTER'S STUDENT · MACHINE LEARNING, DATA SCIENCE, AND ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE · AALTO UNIVERSITY

🛘 (+358) 466144806 | 🔀 prakhar.verma@aalto.fi | 🏕 https://prakharverma.github.io | 🖸 https://github.com/prakharverma | 🗖

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vermaprakhar

Summary_

I am a high energy, confident professional with an infectious enthusiasm for technology. Prior to my masters, I have worked with the R&D department of a multi-national company, a start-up, a public sector company, and an NGO. I possess a track record of good grades, certifications, projects, and presentations.

My research interests are, but not limited to, probabilistic deep learning, Bayesian learning, Gaussian processes, Spatio-temporal modeling, and their application in various fields.

Education

Aalto University Finland

MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.Sc.)

2019 - Present

- Major in Machine Learning, Data Science, and Artificial Intelligence
- Minor in Mathematics
- 4.7/5

Uttarakhand Technical University

India

2012 - 2016

- BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (B.TECH.)
 - Specialization in Information Technology79.03% (First Division with Honors)

Research Experience_

Aalto University Espoo, Finland

RESEARCH ASSISTANT April 2020 - Present

I am a member of the Aalto Machine Learning group headed by Prof. Dr. Arno Solin researching on probabilistic machine learning and latent dynamics.

TomTom Pune, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER(R&D)

July 2016 - August 2019

I was a member of the R&D team which is responsible for devising, developing, and bringing into production various innovative and novel technologies. Majorly, my work revolved around machine learning(semantic segmentation), image processing, and automation with a focus on revolutionizing map data.

Teaching_

Deep Learning (CS-E4070)

Finland

AALTO UNIVERSITY

Spring 2020

- Teaching Assistant
- As one of the teaching assistants for the course, my responsibilities included assignments creation and supervision along with Prof. Dr. Alexander Ilin

Publications

Fuzail Palnak⁺, Kshitij Nikhal⁺, Prakhar Verma⁺, Ravi Panchani⁺, and Sagar Rohankar⁺ "M.A.G.E.C: machine assisted geometry extraction and creation", Proc. SPIE 11433, Twelfth International Conference on Machine Vision (ICMV 2019), 114332Z (31 January 2020); https://doi.org/10.1117/12.2559438; ⁺: Equal contribution

Presentations

12th International Conference on Machine Vision

Amsterdam

PRESENTED: M.A.G.E.C -MACHINE ASSISTED GEOMETRY EXTRACTION AND CREATION

November 2019

Google Developers Group 2018

India

PRESENTED: TENSORFLOW CASE STUDY

April 2018

DECEMBER 3, 2020 PRAKHAR VERMA · RÉSUMÉ HTTPS://PRAKHAR VERMA.GITHUB.IO/

Accomplishments

- Awarded "Dean Scholarship 2020" at Aalto University.
- Awarded "Face of TomTom 2018" for actively representing TomTom in conferences and promoting the brand.
- Winner of TomTom "Innovation Day 2018", presented an artificial intelligence plugin which bridges the gap between machines and cartographers.
- Mentor at "TomTom External Hackathon 2018".
- "Electronic Health Record" idea was selected in Top 10 at a national event, "India Ideathon 2015".

Internships_

TomTom Pune, India

INTERN (BACHELOR THESIS)

January 2016 - June 2016

- Researched and developed a toolkit for on-field map-making
- Thesis was nominated as the most innovative thesis at the university

Instano Technologies Bangalore, India

SOFTWARE INTERN

May 2015 - June 2015

June 2014 - July 2014

December 2014 - January 2015

- I was able to explore the entrepreneur inside me
- Handled both the backend and frontend development of the product

Oil and Natural Gas Dehradun, India

TRAINEE Worked on the development of an "Entry Pass Verification System"

· It helps employees in obtaining the entry pass for their vehicles and security officer in identifying the vehicles

ETASHA Society New Delhi, India

Worked on the testing and roll-out of CRM tool.

Handled the data migration and conducted various training sessions

Projects_

INTERN

Spectral Graph Analysis

AALTO UNIVERSITY November 2019

The project aims to perform graph partitioning with the use of Spectral Clustering on social network graphs. The goal is to minimize the number of cuts while maintaining cluster size balance.

More Details: Github Repository

Bayesian Statistics Global Warming

November 2019 **AALTO UNIVERSITY**

Today, one of the biggest threat to the society is global warming which would cause ice sheets to melt and water volume to expand, resulting in the rising of sea levels. Goal of the project was to examine how much the sea level rise would affect the coastal cities of Finland.

More details: Github Repository

Speaker Adaptation

AALTO UNIVERSITY November 2019

Speaker adaptation uses various techniques to adapt a speech recognition system to user-specific acoustic features. The recognition performance of such systems has not reached that of speaker-dependent ones, though recent development in the processes has proven to improve the recognition results. In this project, we present the various speaker adaptation techniques based on various training methods and their respective results by performance levels (word error rate percentage). More details: Research Paper

More Projects

GITHUB

https://github.com/prakharverma